Hey guys, welcome back.
Now what we have done so far is essentially we lower data,
let the data analysts know that it is available.
They are doing their analysis.
You know, we are building a job.
So bottom line is, you know, we just loaded
one time data for the two year.
It's called historical data, 2024,
and 1 95 will pull data from the NYC portal
and lower data, okay?
But when it comes to productionizing, this, when it comes
to running this data pipeline on a monthly basis
via monthly, because dataset comes monthly, right?
If you go to the TLC portal here,
it comes monthly, okay?
And, uh, with the lag of one or two months, okay?
Like for example, if you are now in January,
you may not see January's data.
You may not even see December's data.
You might, you might see number data here,
giving you an example right now.
Okay? So, but the point is the data is monthly here.
So when it comes to really productionizing this, when
we wanna release every month,
we wanna pull just one month data alone, right?
So the job that you have built now, okay,
you have built three jobs so far, right?
Job number one, which pulled the data from the NYC portal,
uh, to, uh, the raw, right?
This did for about two years of data almost, right?
And second job, uh, was to move from raw
to your, uh, curated.
Again, whatever data was present in the raw folder,
everything, it just took and, uh, transformed that.
So again, two years of data was transformed.
Job number three was to move from curated to aggregated.
Again, whatever was present in, uh, curated
was again aggregated, right?
So right from the job number one to uh, two, the three,
you've been pulling data for the last two years.
I mean, for 2094 and 95 assets, you get the point.
So this is good for a historical onetime rate is fine.
When we go to production, we are in development, then we go
to test environment, then go to production.
So when we go to production environment,
we'll lower the historical data once, okay?
In when you go to production, okay?
So we need to run the historical load once in production,
but for the ongoing load, ongoing monthly load, okay?
We wanna pull just the latest monthly data
that is available, okay?
The question is why, okay? This is very, very important.
The reason why we wanna load only the latest month
information is because the late latest month file
will have the latest month's data only.
There is no chance
that the previous month's information is in this month file.
Okay? How that clear, right?
Let's say, let's say we are now in, uh, January, I assume,
okay, we will,
let's say be gonna getting them number file now, okay?
Because we have a lag, really, we have a lag.
The data gets published, uh,
With, with a lag of one or two months.
So in the November file, there is no chance
that the previous month's data will be there in November.
So that's why we can just load the latest month alone.
Essentially, each month's file contains the data for
that month alone.
That is the reason why we can just pick up that monthly file
and load as a monthly a, uh, aggregation along
with the daily, uh, partitioning as well.
So we gotta now, let's say change our code, right?
Our code just pulls everything.
So we need to have it do two things.
One, history code, two, also pull the latest one.
So we gotta modify the code that does
two things based on the two parameters.
We'll see them shortly. In fact, that is one change.
And the next thing we gotta work on is, see,
you have three jobs here, right?
Three jobs, one, two, and three.
I mean, you cannot really run them out of order.
They have to run in sequence.
One should run before two and two should run before three.
So how do you ensure that when one fails, two doesn't run,
when two fails, three doesn't run,
or when one one fails, two and three doesn't run,
and only when one is successful,
two runs only when two successful three runs,
there's a dependency here.
We gotta set that dependency,
how we'll use a service called a step function.
We'll work on that later.
The third thing is, now we know that this job runs
or rather, is to be run monthly right now.
How do we make sure this job is run monthly?
We gotta schedule this right to run,
let's say on the first of every month.
Now, how do we schedule that using a service called As
Event Bridge?
There are multiple things you gotta
be working on going forward.
It's gonna be very, very interesting.
So make sure you have your seat belts on
and uh, do the hands-on along with me.
See you in the next video.